# ZHENXIANG LIN

🔾 github.com/zhenxianglin 🗞 zhenxianglin.github.io 🔀 zhenxianglin@icloud.com **♀** Sydney, Australia **९** (+61) 457492334

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I received my master's degree in Information Technology from University of New South Wales and bachelor's degree in Electrical Engineering and Automation from Shanghai University of Electric Power. My research interests are in the area of machine and deep learning, computer vision, natural language processing, robotics and related AI applications. Particularly, I have rich experience on Computer Vision and Deep Learning.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Sydney** 

Sydney, Australia Master of Data Science Jul. 2023 - present

**University of New South Wales** 

Sydney, Australia Master of Information Technology — Artificial Intelligence Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2021

Weighted Average Mark: 83.8/100

Selected Coursework: Computer Vision (89/100), Neural Networks and Deep Learning (92/100), Research Project (89/100)

Shanghai University of Electric Power

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Engineering — Electrical Engineering and Automation

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2016

#### **PUBLICATIONS & PRE-PRINTS**

• Zhenxiang Lin, Xidong Peng, Peishan Cong, Yuenan Hou, Xinge Zhu, Sibei Yang, Yuexin Ma. "WildRefer: 3D Object Localization in Large-scale Dynamic Scenes with Multi-modal Visual Data and Natural Language." [arXiv] (submitted to CVPR2024)

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### 3D Vision Grounding on Large-Scale Scenes

ShanghaiTech University

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2023 Supervisor: Yuexin Ma

- Proposed a new task: 3D vision grounding in large-scale dynamic scenes.
- Collected two 3D Vision Grounding datasets on large-scale dynamic scenes.
- Presented a novel method that fully extracts the dynamic feature in images and point clouds to match semantic features in language.
- Compared our method with other methods and achieved the state-of-the-art performance.

#### Multi-Label Long-Tailed Distribution Image Classification

University of New South Wales

Master of IT Research Project, Grade: HD

Jun. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Supervisor: Yang Song

[report]

- Analysed the difference of single-label and multi-label long-tailed distribution.
- Compared the effectiveness of resampling and reweighting strategy.
- Evaluated the effect of different feature extractor on the long-tail distribution datasets.
- Integrated the state-of-the-art methods to achieved a higher performance on two multi-label long-tailed datasets VOC-MLT and COCO-MLT.
- Summarized advantages and disadvantages of different methods.

### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

### Software Development Project

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Built a website using HTML, CSS and Django including registration, login, edit, upload, modify and delete functions.
- Designed a database using PostgreSQL and a set of back-end based routes.
- Used Github for team collaboration.

Data Mining Project Apr. 2021

- Used SVR to predict COVID-19 confirmed cases.
- Tested different feature engineering approaches and evaluated their the effects.

### **Computer Vision Project**

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Conducted a literature review about classic methods and deep learning methods on plants image process.
- Implemented both traditional and deep learning methods including HOG and UNet to perform detection and segmentation.
- Tuned the different parameters to analyse their effects.

# **Neural Network Project**

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Designed both MLP and CNN frameworks for handwritten Hiragana symbols classification.
- Used LSTM and GRU to read business reviews in text format and predict their rating and business category.
- Analysed the effects of different structures.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Research Assistant, ShanghaiTech University, 4DV Lab

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2023

- Collected and cleaned dataset.
- Designed and implemented experiments.
- Analyzed effectiveness of methods by quantitative metrics and visualization.
- Designed a front and back-end separated data annotation system.

### Maintenance Engineer, State Grid Shanghai Municipal Electric Power Company

Sep. 2016 - Mar. 2019

- Operated and maintained substation transformer as well as its associated equipments.
- Managed new substation establishment project.

### **SKILLS**

**Programming Language:** Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Matlab, R

**Deep Learning Framework:** PyTorch, TensorFlow2.0 **Development Framework:** React, Django, Flask

**Database:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

**Libraries:** OpenCV, MMCV, NumPy, scikit-learn, pandas, NLTK, etc.

Others: git, Linux, conda, etc.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

#### Jane Street Market Prediction (Kaggle)

Nov. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• Implemented a MLP model by TensorFlow 2.0 to predict stock data in order to maximize profits. (Top 16%)

# **AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS**

• Award with Excellence, University of New South Wales

2021

• The third prize of excellent student's scholarship, Shanghai University of Electric Power

2012-2014